<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>RimDoctor</name>
  <author>itygr</author>
  <packageId>tyler.rimdoctor</packageId>
  <description>RimDoctor v1.0.3 — a smart in-game mod manager + load/texture/log doctor.

• Prevents missing-texture crashes at runtime by substituting a generated placeholder for any texture that fails to load.
• Reads the live error log and explains it in plain language — what it means, the likely culprit mod, and a suggested fix.
• Scans for broken content (missing textures, bad def paths, incomplete mod downloads) and shows a clear health report.
• Live performance analytics: TPS/FPS, ms-per-tick, memory/GC, and per-mod tick attribution (which mods cost you ticks), plus an optional compact on-screen overlay.
• Startup load-weight and save/world bloat analytics, broken down by mod.
• Suggests a dependency-aware load order (read-only) and repairs problems via a generated local override mod — never by editing Workshop files.

Changelog
v1.0.3 — Fixed the in-game RimDoctor tab not appearing (the packaged release was missing its Defs folder). The tab and version now show in-game.
v1.0.2 — Log window is now OPT-IN (off by default): it no longer auto-pops on every error, which fixes the intrusive UI and audio interruption reported on large mod packs. Removed the auto-apply load-order sort (it could overwrite your modlist). Minor startup fixes.

RimDoctor fails safe: if it errors, it disables the affected feature and never blocks the game from loading.</description>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <!-- Load right after Harmony + Core/DLC so RimDoctor's patches and log/texture
       capture are active before any other mod runs (lets it catch their errors). -->
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.royalty</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.ideology</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.biotech</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.anomaly</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.odyssey</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
